# Hugo Arriojas

Front-End Web Developer

(647)-339-3480 hugo.arriojas@hotmail.com Ottawa, ON

HugoA.dev Github.com/HugoArriojas Linkedin.com/in/HugoArriojas

#### **PROFILE**

I am a web developer, accounting administrator, and marine biologist with experience in data analytics, accounting, and customer service roles.

I build accessible, responsive and user-friendly apps in **React**, **jQuery** and **JavaScript**.

I'm a committed, attentive, empathetic, detail-oriented team player and I have 3 years of experience working remotely. With my experience in project management and strong presentation skills, I aim to bring

SKILLS

## **Web Development**

our designs to life.

HTML

RESTful APIs

CSS

AngularJS

SCSS

Firebase

React

• Git collaboration

JavaScript

Version Control

¡Query

NPM

## Design & Media

Photoshop

Lightroom

Premiere Pro

Figma

#### **Data Analytics**

R / RStudio

MATLAB

ANVIO

• Python

**Accounting** 

**ERP Experience** 

ExcelGAAP

Full-cycle

• AR & AP

# Organization

Notion

JIRA

ADP

CDK

## LANGUAGES

English - Fluent Spanish - Fluent French - Basic

#### **EDUCATION**

**Juno College of Technology** September 2021 to December 2021 Web Development Immersive Bootcamp & JavaScript Course

# **Dalhousie University**

September 2013 to April 2017

Honours Bachelor of Science in Marine Biology & Statistics

## **PROJECTS**

#### **Reactive Retail**

Git, React, API, Firebase, SASS, HTML, CSS, Figma

- · Mock e-commerce site built in React using the FakeStore API.
- Solo project with constant updates adhering to WCAG standards, requiring timeline and project scope estimates.
- Users can filter through products via category, convert prices to different currencies, and add items to their Firebase cart.

Live Link: bit.ly/ReactiveRetail
Git Repo: bit.ly/ReactiveRetailGit

#### The Not So Social Planner

Git, React, API, Firebase, HTML, CSS, Figma

- React project built in agency-style setting from given client brief.
- Acted as project lead, working to develop timelines, handled project scope, and worked as client liaison.
- Project is a social planner where users can submit recurring weekly events and television shows into a Firebase calendar.

**Live Link:** bit.ly/NotSocialPlanner **Git Repo:** bit.ly/NotSocialPlannerGit

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Accounting Administrator**

March 2019 to July 2021

Carson Auto Group, Victoria Ford Alliance

- Reviewed and reconciled banking, warranty, and inventory accounts using CDK software, and claim programs, netting the company over \$20,000 monthly.
- Increased task efficiency by 75% through automation, aimed to create a standardized method for future employees and spearheaded several projects to increase productivity.
- Worked with a team to maintain a large database of records using a variety of accounting software in order to track deals, payments, and inventory.

#### At-Sea Fisheries Observer

January 2018 to November 2018

Archipelago Marine Research

- Gathered, verified, audited, and reported biological and commercial catch data for the Department of Fisheries and Oceans while working in extreme environments.
- Worked as the youngest senior officer on the second largest fishing boat in the world and produced over 480 reports with at least 90% accuracy on estimated catch data.

#### **VOLUNTEER WORK**

# Juno College of Technology

February 2022 (ongoing)

Mentoring and Alumni Office Hours